Tamara Johnson

Versatile Medical/Clerical Candidate

Dallas, TX tcjustice30@yahoo.com 2144441559

Productive and efficient Patient Care Technician with 10 years' experience in obtaining vitals supporting patient needs and providing exceptional service. Superb communication interpersonal organizational and time management abilities, utilizing compassionate-care abilities and clerical skills.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

ICU PCT (Patient Care Technician)

Sagecrest Hospital LTAC specialty - Grapevine, TX July 2018 to Present

- Critical care/long term acute care
- · ostomy care
- trachea
- foley care
- EKG monitor
- dialysis care
- · womb vac care
- jp drains
- peg tubes
- Bedside patient care
- Medhost software
- vitals
- glucose check
- temp
- · in and output recording

PCT (Patient Care Technician) Ortho/Medsurg

Texas Health Presbyterian Hospital - Dallas, TX August 2017 to July 2018

Communicate clearly and openly

Build relationships to promote a collaborative environment

Be accountable for your performance

Always look for ways to improve the patient experience

Take initiative for your professional growth

Be engaged and eager to build a winning team

Meet patients needs with assisting in all daily activities.

Taking initial vitals, collecting specimens, checking glucose, temperature, charting BM Void output. Suction patient as needed per RN delegation

Assist pt with CPM equipment and ice packs, refilling ice machine to apply to operated incision, reposition pt as needed.

Ambulate pt with safety equipment such as walker, gait belt, sliding board.

Set up food trays for pt. Who require more assistance.

Rounding every hour to assure pt. Needs are fulfilled and customer satisfaction.

continually offer fluids or ice in water pitcher if pt. Isn't NPO or fluid restricted.

Patient Care Assistant/ POST OP/Surgical/ LTAC

Phanci Medical Care - Dallas, TX January 2015 to July 2018

Provides patients' personal hygiene by giving bedpans, urinals, baths, backrubs, shampoos, and shaves; assisting with travel to the bathroom; helping with showers and baths.

Provides for activities of daily living by assisting with serving meals, feeding patients as necessary; ambulating, turning, and positioning patients; providing fresh water and nourishment between meals. Observes and reports patient's status and needs.

Answers call lights and attends to/reports patient needs. Get new rooms ready for pending admissions.

PCT (Patient Care Technician)Float Pool Medsurg/Oncolgy/Telemetry

Medical Center of Plano - Plano, TX March 2013 to March 2015

Provides adjunct care by administering enemas, douches, nonsterile dressings, surgical preps, ice packs, heat treatments, sitz and therapeutic baths; applying restraints as directed and rounding for pt. safety

Maintains patient stability by checking vital signs and weight; testing urine; recording intake and output information.

Provides patient comfort by utilizing resources and materials; transporting patients; answering patients' call lights and requests; reporting observations of the patient to nursing supervisor.

Documents actions by completing forms, reports, logs, and records.

Maintains work operations by following policies and procedures.

Protects organization's value by keeping patient information confidential.

Serves and protects the hospital community by adhering to professional standards, hospital policies and procedures, federal, state, and local requirements, and standards.

Hospice Aide

The Hospice Center - Richardson, TX August 2012 to March 2014

Take and record patients' vitals such as pulse, temperature and blood pressure in patient log books

Provide good body alignment and positioning by ensuring that bedridden patients are timely turned and that they air mattresses are in good working order

Assist patients in and out of bed or chairs and encourage range of motion for non-ambulatory patients

Plan and prepare nutritious meals based on each patient's individual needs and assist them in partaking their meals

Report any changes in patient condition to RN

Education

Pharmacy Tech in Pharmacy

Ashworth College - Norcross, GA March 2017 to March 2018

High school or equivalent

Skills

PCT in LTAC/Tracheotomy, CNA (10+ years), Epic system, Meditech, Ensurion, Logitech system, Microsoft, Multi-tasking, Medical Teamwork, Bedside Manner, Infection Control, AIDET (acknowledge, introduce, duration, explanation, thanks, HIPPA, Practice safe Environment, Judgment, Pain Management, Acute/Critical Care (10+ years), Home Health, Dialysis, Certified Nursing Assistant (10+ years), CPR (10+ years), Patient Care, Cna Certified

Certifications/Licenses

CNA 0876006

CPR

Pharmacy Tech Trainee